Actually it is less difficult but it is very difficult. There
are 27 insurance companies
in Arun and almost 130 insurance policies
or health insurance policies, so it is
very difficult for you to do anything. That is why to
make your insurance journey easy, we bring you a video comparison so that
you can choose a
suitable health and health insurance
policy for your family. Today we have brought
for you a comparison video on Short 2.o and
ICC Lombard Health Advantage.
Before starting the video, I would
like to introduce myself. My name is
Goodlink Gota. I am a Certified
Financial Planner. Every week I bring a video for you so that
your personal
financial life and insurance bank
journey can be made happy because the
tagline of our company is also
creating a wealth of happiness. Let's move
towards the video and this Short 2 vs
ICC Lombard Health Advantage. First we will
talk about the claim settlement
ratio of both.  In terms of these cut claim ratios,
Nava's claim settlement ratio is 90.12% and
its claim ratio is
62.18.75% and its claim ratio is 91.67%. There are
around 11000 network
hospitals, Lombard has almost 5500
hospitals. Here both the companies have a
green house clean settlement team, there is
no external third party administrator, it is an in
house clean settlement team which
settles your claims. Now let's move
towards the product, first we will talk about
what is the unique selling point of
both the products. The
unique selling point of Nava 2.2 is the lock de clock
feature in which your premium does
not increase until you make a claim. So the
premium of Entry AIDS Lab is relief until
you make a claim. The second benefit
is Booster Plus, whatever your unutilized data is, it gets carried forward.
Whatever you are not utilizing, every benefit gets carried forward.  The yearly tax will be
forwarded to you. 10x options
are available, I will discuss that later.
Now let's talk about ICC Lombard's
ceiling points. The
biggest unique selling point of ICC Lombard Health is
its guaranteed cumulative bonus. This
means that the no-claim bonus given to you, which is
20% every year, increases to
100% and does
not reduce. If you take it clean, then
once a life time, this is
an advantage. Secondly, if someone is
looking at the maternity option, then it
is available in ICC Lombard Health Advantage.
You can take maternity after nine
months. Newborn baby expenses and
vaccination expenses will also be included in it.
Here, you have to pay three years'
premium together upfront and
after that your maternity tax will be settled after nine
months. Now let's talk about the basic
eligibility criteria.
In this Shot 2.0, the entry is after
18 years for adults and the maximum entry is
after 65. Minimum it is 18, maximum 65 and
if children are entering then
children can enter after 91 days and
dependent children can continue
till 30 years. In this, the minimum entry in Number Health and Vantage is after
18 years for adults and maximum
65 and children get added after 91 days
and children can continue
in the policy till 25 years. Policy type: So, by
policy type, you can take an individual policy, a
family floater, or a divisible policy.
You will
get a detailed video on this on our channel about which is an individual
policy, which is a policy
and which is a family lot of policy.
What are the differences in them, you
can prefer that. In all, we will talk about Shot
2.2, we will
talk about premium increase, so premium
increase is after 5 years in both the policies.  If it is
paid then your premium does
not increase every year. 8 slabs of five years each
are defined and
your premium increases accordingly. Policy time and
policy tenure are available in both the policies for
one, two and three years. If you
want, you can take a multi-year policy. If you
take a policy for two years and three years together, then the
company gives you additional discount
on insurance. In short 2.2, if you
take a policy for two years together, then you get 7.5%
discount on the second year premium. If you
take a policy for three years together, then you get 15%
discount on the third premium.
In ICC Lombard Health Advantage, if you
take a policy for two years together, then you get 7.5% discount
on the total premium and if you take a policy for three years
together, then you will talk about 10% discount on the total
premium, which is a very
important factor. When you go to buy a health and
insurance policy, there is
no romantic gaming in both. You
can do anything as per your wish.
Now we will talk about bonuses.  There are
different policies like
this shot on Neem is in point O, Booster Plus
Benefit. Booster Plus Benefit is if
you are not facing any problem then it
always shows that your tax will be carried forward. So for
example, if you have taken a policy of Rs. 10 lakh and
you have not paid the premium for the next policy, then the Rs.
10 lakh of the last policy which
you had not paid will be carried
forward. In this, this is called
Booster Plus. There are two variants
available here, Platinum Plus and Titanium
Plus. If you take Platinum Plus, then your tax will be up to 5x. If you
take Titanium Plus, then
your tax will be up to a maximum of Rs. 10x. Bronze
Plus is also available which was
introduced later, in which the tax will be up to 3x.
ICC Lombard Health Advantage has a
no claim bonus which is also called
guaranteed cumulative bonus of 20% every year
and the maximum will go up to 100%. If
any claim is made in the future, then no claim will be made. The
Care Benefit The Care Benefit is
covered in both the policies.  Yes, you always get
home health care benefit, my uncle, but
in SHOT 2.0 it is available on cashless basis and ICC
number is up to 25000. Domiciliary hospital
Dombivali hospital is available in those conditions
where the patient is not in a condition to be taken to the
hospital or
beds are not available in the hospital, then both the conditions are also called
home hospitalization, so
both of them are called film benefit, so
refill benefit is available in both the policies,
refill benefit is basically
when your base exhaustion happens, whether
partial or full exhaustion, then
your refill benefit gets triggered in that case,
so the name you have mentioned above is
refill benefit in SHOT 2.2, and plus in this
you will get refilled unlimited number of times
if your base exhaustion happens and this is
also a special thing about this SHOT class that
if this shot gets triggered for the first time, if the
film benefit gets triggered then it remains
with you every year  The praise will keep getting forwarded. The
refill benefit in ICC Lombard Health Advantage is from
this one, air or other
illness, if your base gets exhausted then you
can refill once, your base
OPD benefit is available in both, at
this point
you can add Quote Care as an add-on
rider in it there are two options, Best Concert
and Best Care, so you can add it.
ICC Lombard Health Advantage also has a
Fit Rider in which you
can add OPD benefits for yourself, the
detailed video of all this
is already available on our channel, you can refer the
expenses, so the expenses before hospitalization
and the expenses after hospitalization are covered,
60 days free
and monetary benefit,
post hospitalization expenses will also be covered in both the policies,
if
not Mamu, then these will be given in Short 2.0 today,
1% off time in ICC Lombard Health Advantage  A shot or ₹10,000
whichever is lower per incident will be paid to you.
Clear ambulance so and ambulance
again emergency and ambulance and domestic
and ambulance are covered. There is a
tax of 2.2 lakhs in this short 2.5 lakhs.
Domestic and ambulance are covered in ICC Lombard Advantage. All other
treatments and robotics surgeries are covered
in both the policies. Modern treatments and
vertex surgeries are covered in this short 2.2 lakhs.
In this short 2.5 lakhs is the term for modern treatments in this short 2.2 lakhs.
Except for some surgeries, robotics is covered in four surgeries. There
is a sub limit of 1 lakhs for all other surgeries. In ICC Lombard Advantage,
your modern treatments
are covered up to your submission.
Organ donor expenses are taxed in both the policies
and remember that always the
harvesting cost is taxed. Organ
donor expenses mean all the expenses of the donor will
not be taxed, which means
whatever expenses are incurred at the time of donating the organ, the
process, the harvesting cost, will be
paid and the rest of the expenses will not be taxed.  There is also an
eye consultation.
Unlimited eye consultations are available in both the policies.
You can consult a doctor from their partner network, which is a
consultation.
Worldwide
coverage is never available here. There is no worldwide coverage in this policy like
Lombard Health Advantage etc. If you
take a policy above ₹25 lakh, then
worldwide coverage is available and is settled in
cashless through your partner which is
Felt International and 10% of that is charged
in any AYUSH AYUSH related
hospital which is Ayurveda, Dr.
Unani, Dr. Homeopathy, their hospitals are
available in both the plans.
Now let's talk about complimentary annual health
checkup. Annual health checkup is available in both the policies.
In this policy it is ₹500 per shot. So
if you have a policy of ₹10 lakh, then if you have a policy of ₹5000, then ₹
10000 maximum.  ₹10,000 will be given
in an family floater policy.
₹5,000 in an individual policy. In ICC Lombard
Health Advantage, 0.5% maximum
in 100 policies. You can avail annual health checkup.
You have taken the policy today and
you can claim from the first policy itself. You do
n't need to wait for renewal, which
is a complimentary annual checkup.
Consumables are available
in both the policies.
In this Shot
Plus Rider on Lemon, you can take the same rider and
in ICC Lombard Health Advantage, you
can also add the Consumables Rider. So, there are
some discounts
in both the policies which I would like to highlight to you. I would like to highlight
this Shot Plus discount above
which we talked about initially. If you
take a policy for 2 years or 3 years together, then you will be given a
discount of 7.5% on the second policy and
15% on the third policy. The second is the standing
instruction discount. If you want that  If
your policy gets auto debited on renewal, if the
premium gets debited and the
policy gets renewed automatically, then
you will be given a 2.5% discount. Third is the multi-
individual discount which is 10%
and 4 Live Healthy Benefit discount. If
you maintain an active lifestyle, then
you get a discount of 30%. Such people,
first discount in Advantage is your
multi-individual discount. If you take a two-year policy
together, you get a 7.5% discount on the total
premium and a 10% discount on three years. The
second discount is if you
enroll for a soft copy. If you say that I do
not want a hard copy, then the
company gives you a discount of ₹100. There is
also a vaccine discount. If you have taken the pneumococcal
vaccine, then also you are given a discount in the policy.
ICC Lombard
Health and Technology Now let's talk about
optional benefits.
What optional benefits are available in both the policies, which you
can add as extra premium.
In 2.2, the first optional benefit is Safeguard, second is Safety
Cut Plus Personal Accident Care, fourth  There
is hospital cash benefit. Fifth is disease
management rider, which we
call disease management rider of Qute Care.
Another subsection of Qute Care is OPD
benefit, which has two features, Best Care and Best Concert.
In ICC Lombard Health and Advantage, your optional riders are
firstly maternity benefit which we talked about,
which we can add, newborn baby
care and vaccination care are also included, you
can also add sum in short protector
and claim protector,
then there are your riders,
you can also add personal accident by paying additional
premium and along with that there is BP trade which is
their OPD benefit rider, you can also add that. Regarding
waiting periods, there are
some waiting periods in both the plans, like
in every health and care policy, you have
waiting periods. The initial waiting
period is 30 days. In both the plans, there is a
waiting period for slow growing illnesses which is
specified.  Exclusions are
also called Specific Explosions, it has a
waiting period of 24 months. In both the policies, the
meeting period for all existing conditions is
36 months and in Nibabu, this Short 2.2
ICC Lombard Health Advantage is 24 months
and we will also talk about the waiting
period for maternity because that is a rider.
In ICC Lombard Health Advantage, you
can add a waiting period of 9 months
and you have to pay a premium of 3 years upfront for
that maternity benefit. Now let's talk about the
premium scheme. In Nibabu, this
Short 2.2 is divided into Zone 1 and Zone 2 zones
and the
premium is charged accordingly. So, the premium for this is
lower. So here I
would like to tell you that if you are paying the premium for Zone 2
and if you are
taking treatment in this zone, then there is no payment,
you can easily take the treatment.
The story
is slower than Zone 1 and if you are taking treatment in this zone, then there is no payment.
If you are taking treatment in John then there is a 10%
payment. If you are taking treatment in John then there is a
15% payment. You have the
option to select the premium for John mother.
If you do not want any contribution then
you can do that. Now I will
share some premium with you on a family
of four. Here I have taken 45, 39, 17 and
12 as family sizes and I am
sharing the premium for John 1 with you. So
this is about Niwabu. This is short 2.2
from my side. If you have any questions,
you can rate us in the comment section. You can also share your WhatsApp
number and email ID. And if you
want guidance on the policy or want to buy a policy, then
they have a dedicated service
which helps you. You
can find us below. Quick reminder before you know it.
If you have not subscribed to our channel yet, do
subscribe on date. You can do right
information and at the right time. See you
soon in the next video. Take care.
Bye bye.